《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》前情回顾
STARBUCK: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我还能活几个月
I have a few months to live.
在这段时间里  我将带领人民脱离苦难
And in that time, I will lead the people to salvation.
这是我个人意愿
It is my sole purpose.
赞美主
Praise be to the Gods.
这就是我们的救世主
Here is our salvation.
劳拉·罗丝琳在军中唆使他人兵变
Laura Roslin's actions in suborning mutiny and sedition
煽动暴乱是无法容忍的
among the military could not be tolerated.
因此阿达玛指挥官别无选择
Therefore, Cdr. Adama was left with no choice
只能解除她的权利
other than to remove her from office.
我得马上从这里出去
We've got to get out of here now.
我和你在一起
I'm right with you.
我看这些人也许真的是人类
I think these guys might really be human.
卡布里卡上的人都死光了
Everyone on Caprica's dead.
你就没死
You're not.
我刚到这儿
I just got here.
算不上是一支军队
Not exactly an army.
可要比我们两人只身…
A hell of a lot better than the two of us
攻打一座空军基地
if we're gonna assault an airbase,
还要偷个重装突袭机逃离这该死的星球强多了
steal a Heavy Raider, and get the frak off this planet.
很高兴知道把安装金字塔球场
Nice to know installing a regulation Pyramid court
作为反抗军的头等大事
was one of the priorities of the Resistance.
投的好
Nice shot.
谢了
Thanks.
站到一边或杀了我
Stand aside or you can shoot me.
我要通过那扇舱门  离开这船
I intend to go through that hatch and get off this ship.
前任总统失踪  失踪?
The former president's missing. Missing?
两人受伤  牢里没人
Two men down. Cell's empty.
该死的
Damn it.
我们暂时安全了
APOLLO: Well, we're home free for now.
见到你真好  总统女士
Glad to see you, Madam President.
泽瑞克是这里唯一
Zarek here is the only one
可以为我们提供庇护的人
with enough shady friends around who can possibly hide us.
叛徒
ALL: Traitor!
凯莉开枪击中了布玛儿
MAN: Cally shot Boomer!
不  不  不
TYROL: No, no. No.
我爱你  上士
I love you, Chief.
我的船上出了什么事
What's happening on my ship?
我把事情办砸了
I frakked things up and good.
我做了一些错误的决定
I made some bad calls.
还有很多事需要处理
A lot of pieces to pick up.
那我们就一起来处理
Then we'll pick them up together.
通过
Go through.
你醒了1个小时了?
You've been awake for an hour?
如果你无法返回你的战舰  怎么办?
So what're you gonna do if you can't make it back to your ship?
我能回去
I'm getting back.
我倒知道可以把你这冒失鬼带哪去
Well, I know we were able to take your sorry ass by surprise.
去你的
Frak you.
说的好  可实际情况是…
Nice. But the truth is,
我们根本不知道在干什么
we really don't know what the hell we're doing.
许多战术布置和其他东西都是从电影里学的
A lot of our tactics are stuff we just saw in the movies.
我们需要一些专家的指点
We could use some professional advice.
想要我指点一下?
You want some advice?
你们在这场战争中已经处于劣势
You're on the losing end of this fight.
在你们都死光以前还是趁早放弃吧
Give it up before you all die.
向山上去  远离外界的辐射
Head further up in the mountains, above the ambient radiation,
然后躲起来
and just hole up.
然后呢?  等死吗?
And what? Wait to die?
我一回到卡拉狄加就会派救援队
As soon as I get back to Galactica, I'll send a rescue party.
说的倒好听
Yeah, right.
我说到做到
If I say I'm gonna do something, I do it.
你早上一起来就这么犯贱吗?
You always such a bitch in the morning?
你就等着吧
Count on it.
我喜欢这样的女人
My kind of woman.
我们还有任务在身
Hey. We have a mission to accomplish.
那又怎样?
So what?
有任务
Mission.
好啦  随便
Fine. Whatever.
对不起  好了吧?
I'm sorry, okay?
我不是故意要...
I didn't mean to...
骗到你了
Got you.
真差劲  真是太差劲了
So weak. So, so very weak.
必须要找点乐子
Lighten up a little bit.
世界末日了
It's only the end of the world.
苏尚  你来把守封锁线
Sue-Shaun, I want you to watch our perimeter,
特别留意我们的侧翼
especially on the flank.
好
Okay.
赛昂人在山脊那边
The Cylons have a refueling airstrip
有一座补给燃料的小型机场
just on the other side of that ridge.
每天下午都有一架重型突袭机
There's a Heavy Raider, makes a regular refueling stop
按时在那里补给
every afternoon, like clockwork.
机器喜欢按规矩办事  恩
HELO: Machines like routine. SAM: Yeah.
通常来说有3名赛昂武士看守
It's usually guarded by less than three of the mechanical varieties.
在此之前我们还没进攻过那里
We've left it alone up until now.
所以呢? 什么计划?
HELO: So what's the plan?
从这条沟里走  从南侧接近小型机场
Go through this gully, approach the airstrip from the south side,
我们的人分布在树木线里
sprinkle our men through the tree line,
等突袭机降落后
wait for the Cylons to land the Raider,
钩住燃料管
hook up the refueling hoses.
一旦他们钩住了锑砾钼燃料管
Once they hook up the tylium hoses,
我们就干掉守卫  炸掉补给站
we take out the guards and blow their refueling station.
你不是说要一架完好无损的突袭机吗?
I thought you wanted the Raider intact?
相信我  那东西结实着呢
They build them tough. Believe me.
炸毁补给站不会伤到船体一分一毫
Blowing the fuel will barely put a scratch on the hull,
可也许给了我们上船的时间
but it might give us enough time to board the Raider.
我一上船
Once I'm inside,
就去毁掉它的大脑  然后开始研究如何把我们...
I'll blow the brain, and I'll start working on trying to get it...
撤后  有敌情
MAN 1: Stay back! Over there!
开火
MAN 2: Open fire!
卡拉  隐蔽
SAM: Kara, take cover!
回来
Get back!
都撤退 卡拉 快走
Everybody fall back! Fall back! Kara, let's go!
阿达玛 阿达玛…
ALL: Adama! Adama! Adama!
非常感谢各位  我很高兴重返岗位
Thank you very much. I'm glad to be back.
有些事用不着说出来  但心里明白
There are things we don't say often enough,
像是我们彼此在对方心目中的地位
things like what we mean to one another.
你们大家对我来说都非常重要
All of you mean a lot to me.
我只想让你们知道这一点
I just want you to know that.
大家回去工作吧
Let's get back to work.
我感觉有些奇怪
I feel strange. Like...
摇摇欲坠的感觉
Closer to the ground.
你该去看看医生
You should check in with the doctor.
盖塔先生
Mr. Gaeta?
你认为他们现在在那里?
Where do we think they are now?
载有阿波罗上尉...
The stolen Raptor with Capt. Adama
和前任总统的猛禽号...
and the former president.
逃犯
The fugitives.
逃犯上周在星云九号入港
The fugitives docked at Cloud 9 last week.
因为大量船只在星云九号出入
We effectively lost them at that point
我们实际上已经找不到他们了
due to the large volume of inter-fleet traffic going to and from Cloud 9.
他们现在可能在舰队中的任何地方
By now, they could be holed up anywhere in the fleet.
要找到他们
I want them found.
作为反抗的标志来说  她已经够危险的了
She was dangerous enough as a symbol of Resistance,
现在还有了李的协助
but now with Lee helping...
搜查舰队中的各个船只
I wanna search every ship in the fleet.
隔离程序
Quarantine procedures.
把船和舰队主体隔离
Isolate the ship out of the main body.
如果船上没有发现他们
If it's clean,
我们就让它远离其他船只
we keep it quarantined away from the rest of the fleet.
她可以躲起来  但却跑不掉
She can hide, but she can't run.
小杜  执行隔离程序
Dee, start quarantine procedures.
从星云九号开始
Start with Cloud 9.
我们还要在这肉库里呆多久?
ROSLIN: How much longer are we meant to stay hidden in this meat locker?
不知道
ELOSHA: I don't know.
我已经把你的口信传给了12法人团体
I communicated your latest message to the Quorum of 12
他们决定就支持你的问题上来讲还需要再...
and they've decided that the question of openly supporting you
慎重考虑一下
needs more deliberation.
我要呼吁大众
I need to make an appeal to the people.
给他们一个充分的理由
Make a strong enough argument
星际女皇将首当其冲
and the Astral Queen will be the first ship in line.
看来他们什么事都干 就是不听你的调遣
Like they do anything but roll over and take orders from you.
我还要转达一件事
One more bit of news I should convey.
宙斯回归奥林匹克山了
Zeus has returned to Olympus.
阿达玛重掌帅印了
Adama's back in command.
我父亲回来了?
My father? He's back?
无线电上听到的
ZAREK: Word just came in over the wireless.
强悍的老头子
He is a tough old bird.
我们需要的是一些真心诚意的东西
ZAREK: What we really need is something heartfelt,
一些有人情味东西 这样能让人们支持我们
something human and personal that will galvanize the people.
例如一个谴责自己父亲的儿子
Like a son denouncing his father.
我叫李·阿达玛
My name is Lee Adama.
直到最近我还是卡拉狄加的空军指挥官
Until recently, I was the commander of Galactica's air group,
可当阿达玛指挥官  我的父亲...
but when Cdr. Adama, my father,
决定实施军事政变反抗总统的时候
decided to stage a military coup against the President,
我不能再支持他或他的行为了
I could no longer support him or his actions.
我爱我的父亲
I love my father.
我尊重他
I respect him.
但在这件事上...
But in this,
他错了
he is wrong.
我必须要反对他
He must be opposed.
我呼吁舰队里所有思想自由的人士
I call on all free-thinking people in the fleet. I...
我做不来  抱歉  各位
I can't do this. Sorry, everyone.
我以为自己可以  但还是不行
I thought I could, but I can't.
我要打"宗教"这张牌了
I'm playing the religious card.
我知道到底该怎么做
I know exactly what I have to do.
这东西怎么用?
How does this thing work?
没事了
SIMON: You're okay.
你在一家急救中心
You're in an aid hospital.
他们昨天早上把你送来的
They brought you in yesterday morning.
你腹部中弹了
You got shot in the abdomen.
我叫西蒙
I'm Simon.
能告诉我你的名字吗?
Can you tell me your name?
卡拉
Kara.
卡拉·瑟瑞丝
Kara Thrace.
你的手术用了两个小时
SIMON: You were in surgery for about two hours.
我取出了子弹
I removed the bullet.
没想到你能挺过来
I didn't think you were gonna make it there for a while.
放松
Take it easy.
我知道很疼
I know that hurts.
谁把我送来的?
Who brought me in?
一个叫安德斯的高个子
This big guy named Anders.
信不信由你  他以前是打职业金字塔球赛的
Used to be a pro Pyramid player, if you can believe that.
恩  我认识他
Yeah, I know him.
他在哪里?
Where is he?
他在手术台上死了
He died. On the table.
我原以为只是轻伤
I thought he was only slightly wounded.
结果一块弹片划开了他的大动脉
It turns out a piece of shrapnel had nicked his aorta.
内部大出血
Massive internal bleeding.
抱歉  我们已经尽力了
I'm sorry. We did everything we could do.
早上好
SIMON: Good morning.
看来你的点滴打得挺快  不错
I see you're sucking down fluids at a rapid pace. That's good.
你是赛昂人吗?
Are you a Cylon?
你说呢?
What do you think?
我说你还没回答问题
I think you didn't answer the question.
我绝不可能是赛昂人
I am most definitely not a Cylon.
当然我不知道你想让我怎么说
Of course, I don't know what you'd expect me to say.
如果我真是赛昂人  我当然也不会承认
If I was a Cylon, I certainly wouldn't admit it.
我能走了吗?
Can I leave?
门在那里
There's the door.
去他妈的医生
Frakking doctors.
那我是医生而不是赛昂人?
So I am a doctor, not a Cylon?
悬而未决
The jury's still out.
可我以为赛昂人更会嘲弄人
I would expect the Cylons to have better digs than this, though.
这医院在那里?
Where is this rattrap?
我们在特尔斐南部22公里的地方
We're about 20 clicks north of Delphi.
这里曾是精神病院
Used to be a mental institution.
本不值得一提 但这是为数不多赛昂人还没发现的地方
It's not much, but it's one of the few places the Cylons haven't found yet.
好吧
Okay.
那又怎么样?要我相信…
So, what, I'm supposed to believe
外面真的有反抗军吗?
there really is a Resistance out there?
别说话
Don't tell anybody.
安静
We're trying to keep that quiet.
该打止痛针了
Time for your pain meds.
我能替凯莉技师说几句话吗
TYROL: If I may speak on behalf of Specialist Cally?
因为在科波上的经历 她当时心神意乱
She was distraught through the experience on Kobol.
在那里与赛昂人战斗
Being on the surface, fighting the Cylons,
我们都崩溃了
it's shattering for all of us.
我认为她在向布玛儿开枪的时候 她有些精神失常
I don't believe she was in her right mind when she shot Boomer.
你爱她吗  上士?
Did you love her, Chief?
什么?
Excuse me?
布玛儿  你爱她吗?
Boomer. Did you love her?
我想是的
I thought I did.
当你认为你爱某人的时候  你爱她
When you think you love somebody, you love them.
那就是爱  一种想法
That's what love is: thoughts.
她是一个赛昂人  一部机器
She was a Cylon, a machine.
那就是布玛儿吗?一部机器?
Is that what Boomer was? A machine?
一样东西
A thing?
事实如此
That's what she turned out to be.
对我们来说  她可不止如此
She was more than that to us.
对我来说  也不只如此
She was more than that to me.
她是一个活生生的人
She was a vital, living person
在我船上呆了快两年
aboard my ship for almost two years.
她不可能只是一部机器
She couldn't have been just a machine.
你能去爱一部机器吗?
Could you love a machine?
不能  长官  我想不能
No, sir. I guess I couldn't.
凯莉在未经许可的情况下开枪
Cally discharged a firearm without permission,
危及了她的战友的生命
endangering the lives of her shipmates.
关30天禁闭
30 days in the brig.
解散
Dismissed.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
你还会再见到她的  上士
You'll see her again, Chief.
什么?
Excuse me?
有许多复制体
There are many copies.
你还会见到她的
You'll see her again.
这里有多少病人?
How many patients do you have here?
又要审问我吗?
Am I being interrogated again?
我只是觉得奇怪
I just think it's odd
来这里两天了
that I've been here for two days,
还没见到其他人
and I haven't seen anybody else.
只有你
Just you.
我们现在这有223名患者
We have 223 patients at the moment,
2名医生 5名冒充是护士的教师
two doctors, and five teachers masquerading as nurses.
我认识一个冒充是总统的教师
I know a teacher masquerading as president.
什么?
What's that?
太安静了
It's awfully quiet.
没有尖叫  没有呻吟
No screams, no moans, no
没人说"医生  医生  快救救我  好疼"
"Doctor! Doctor! Please help me! It hurts. "
我们的大部分患者都死于急性放射中毒
Most of our patients are succumbing to acute radiation poisoning.
症状包括疲乏无力以及突然恶心
Symptoms include powerful fatigue and immediate nausea.
这些都是在几天的相对安宁之后出现的
This is followed by several days of comparable well-being.
在那之后  胃部与小肠组织的细胞坏死..
After that, cell death in the gastric and intestinal tissue causes
导致频繁的腹泻  小肠出血  脱水
massive diarrhea, intestinal bleeding, and loss of water.
那场面可不好看
It's not pretty.
但却很安静
But it is quiet.
这地方最大的杀手就是感染
The biggest killer in this place is infection.
所以才隔离你
That's why we have you under quarantine.
我们还不知道你带来了什么
We don't know what you brought in with you yet.
你的化验结果下午就会出来了
Your test results will be back this afternoon.
好  快好了
Okay, almost done.
我想你的一个卵巢中有一块囊肿
I think there may be a cyst on one of your ovaries.
严重吗?
Is it serious?
不  应该没事
No, it should be fine.
我们会留意的
We'll keep an eye on it.
要保持生殖系统的健康
Gotta keep that reproductive system in great shape.
这是当今情况下你最宝贵的财产了
That's your most valuable asset these days.
可不吗
Right.
我是说真的
I'm serious.
寻找你这个岁数的健康怀孕女子
Finding healthy, child-bearing women your age
是反抗军的头等大事
is a top priority for the Resistance,
你是非常珍贵的商品
and you'll be happy to know
可是件高兴事
that you are a very precious commodity to us.
我不是一件商品
I am not a commodity.
我是一名蝮蛇战机的驾驶员
I'm a Viper pilot.
你看见这附近有蝮蛇战机了吗?
You see any Vipers around here?
你知道你可是这星球上剩下的为数不多的
I mean, you do realize that you're one of a handful of women
可以怀孕的女性  对吧?
left on this planet actually capable of having children, right?
这可是你现在最珍贵的技能
I mean, that is your most valuable skill right now.
我不想要孩子  别提了  好吗?
Well, I don't want a child, so just drop it, okay?
没人强迫你
Well, no one's forcing you.
花些时间好好想想吧
Just take a moment
你现在的位置  现在是怎么回事
and think about where you are and what's going on.
人类在灭绝的边缘
The human race is on the verge of extinction.
非常坦率地说
And, to be quite frank with you, potential mothers
当前可能成为母亲的人要比
are a lot more valuable right now
整个蝮蛇战机编队珍贵的多
than a whole squadron of Viper pilots.
我不该提这些
I shouldn't have mentioned it.
该知道你会很敏感的
I should've known you'd be sensitive.
在你之前许多和你有类似经历的女人
A lot of women with your history
都怀上了她们自己的孩子
forego bearing children of their own.
我的经历?
My history?
我在你的X光上看到了骨折
I saw the fractures on your X-rays.
许多童年时候的旧伤
A lot of old fractures from childhood.
有趣的是
It's interesting
你如何设法把10指折断的
how you managed to break every finger on both hands.
骨折都是在
Every break in the exact same place,
第一关节与第二关节之间的相同位置
between the first and the second knuckle.
有人把你的手指折断过吗  卡拉?
Did someone break your fingers, Kara?
出去
Get out.
遭受父母虐待的孩子
Children of abusive parents
通常来说都害怕将来会虐待自己的孩子
often fear passing along that abuse to their own children.
滚出去!
Get out!
好
All right.
她是拿这东西开玩笑吗?
Is she kidding with this?
难以置信
I know it's hard to believe,
可那消息已经遍布在舰队的各个地方
but that message has cropped up all over the fleet.
这是宗教上的一派胡言
It's religious crap.
看来我已被选为带领你们
"It seems I have been chosen to help lead you
前往地球上 那片希望大陆的人
"to the promised land of Earth.
我不会对这个选择提出置疑
"I will not question this choice.
而只想尽量扮演好我在这个计划中的角色
"I will simply try to play my part in the plan.
因此  在指定好的时间...
"Therefore, at the appointed hour,
我会在舰队里发出信号...
"I will give a signal to the fleet.
那些希望尊重神灵和走上宿命道路的人
"All those wishing to honor the gods and walk the path of destiny
就跟着我回到科波
"will follow me back to Kobol.
我们将带着阿波罗之箭
"It is there that we will meet
与神的仆人在那里相会
"the gods' servant with the Arrow of Apollo. "
有5架猛禽号载满陆战队员的火力小组
We've got five Raptors with marine fire-teams standing by
准备好登上星际女皇
to board the Astral Queen.
不会有人追随她的
No one's gonna follow her.
没人会相信这鬼话
No one's gonna believe this crap.
没人会那么傻
No one's this stupid.
如果有人想回到科波自寻死路的话
And anyone that is, that wants to make a suicide run to Kobol,
请让他们去吧
please let them.
还有多久我们才能空间跳跃
ROSLIN: How long till we jump?
两分钟
Two minutes.
还有其他船只宣称追随我们吗?
Any other ships declared themselves for us?
还没有
Not yet.
不  请不用这样  没必要这样
No, that... No, please, this isn't necessary.
祝福他们吧
Give them your blessing.
不  不对  我不是--
Oh, no. It's not right. It isn't who I am.
劳拉  这是你的宿命
Laura, this is your path,
这是神为你选择的...
the one the gods picked for you,
也是你自己选择的道路
the one you picked for yourself.
苏尚
Sue-Shaun!
安德斯  我们都已经来回搜了10遍了
HELO: Anders, we must have been over this line 10 times already.
她一定是中枪了
She must have taken a bullet.
当时就在车边上
She was right here by the vehicles.
她可能起来后 艰难的离开这鬼地方
She would have got up and crawled the frak out of here.
我们还要再搜查一下这片区域
Hey, we have to search the entire area again.
我告诉过你我们不该撤得那么快
I told you we shouldn't have pulled back so fast.
我还以为她和我们在一起
I thought she was with us.
安德斯  我们中了埋伏
Anders, we got ambushed, okay?
大家都分开了 这也是没办法的事
We all got separated. There's nothing we could have done about it.
卡拉和大家都明白这一点
Kara, of all people, would understand.
还是找到她再说吧
Let's just find her.
等一下  等等
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
我知道星芭儿在哪里
BOOMER: I know where Starbuck is.
莎伦?
Sharon?
你去哪里了?
Where have you been?
跟踪你  她是谁?
Tracking you. Who is she?
自己人
She's with us.
你是我的孩子的父亲
BOOMER: You're the father of my child, Helo.
我不会丢下你不管
I'm not gonna lose you.
她在哪里?
Where is she?
准备好了
ZAREK: We're ready.
发射信号  然后跳跃
Send the signal and jump.
星际女皇跳跃走了
Astral Queen has jumped away.
现在看有多少人追随她
Now we'll see how many follow.
坐在原地等着星芭儿…
To sit around and wait for Starbuck
带来那可笑的阿波罗之箭
to show up with that stupid arrow?
最多两  三艘
Two, three at the most.
早上好
Good morning.
你看起来好多了
You look better.
这新伤疤是怎么回事?
What's this new scar?
昨晚在你睡觉的时候 他们不得不再进行手术
You had to go back in last night while you were asleep.
止住了内出血的部位  没什么好担心的
Some internal bleeding to tie up. Nothing to worry about.
一切都会好起来的
Everything's gonna be fine.
你快好了  星芭儿
We're just about done with you, Starbuck.
挺会安慰人的
Nice way of putting it.
再做几个化验  还有…
Just a couple more tests, and...
我差点说成要把你送回家了
I almost said, "We'll be sending you back home. "
我看该说让你重新投入战斗
I guess we'll be sending you back into the fight.
听来不错
That sounds good to me.
我刚醒
Hey, I just woke up.
现在该好好睡觉了
And now you're going back to sleep.
你是医生  你说了算
You're the doc.
等待实验室的卵巢样本化验结果
SIMON: Pending lab-test results on sample ovaries,
明天将进行完全切除
complete removal will proceed tomorrow.
如果化验结果呈阳性 该对象将被移送到…
If lab tests are positive, then subject will be removed
配置机构做最终审理
to processing facility for final disposition.
你的语气有些后悔之意啊  西蒙?
NO. 6: Is that regret I hear in your voice, Simon?
如果有的话  当然也不关你的事
If it is, it certainly is none of your concern.
科波之主  求您救我
Lords of Kobol, please help me.
早上好
Good morning.
你确定你没事吗?
Are you sure you're feeling okay?
近来是有些不舒服
You know, something actually has been bothering me lately.
我从没和你说过我的代号是星芭儿
I never told you my call sign was Starbuck.
你是杀不死我的
You can't kill me.
去死吧!
Just die!
苏尚  苏尚  是我  卡拉
Sue-Shaun. Sue-Shaun, it's me, Kara.
挺住  我救你出来
Hold on, okay? I'm gonna get you out of here.
不  没时间了
No, no time.
切断电源
Cut the power.
那样你会死的
That'll kill you.
我不想像这样活下去
Can't live like this.
婴儿机
The baby machines.
求你了
Please.
你好  星芭儿
SIMON: Hello, Starbuck.
卡拉  快过来
Kara, come on!
快  冲啊
Let's go! Let's go! Go! Go!
爬下  卡拉  爬下
Get down! Kara, get down!
走  快走
Come on! Let's go!
要走啦
Gotta go!
快!
Hey.
快!提起精神!快上来!快!
Come on! Move like you have a purpose, people! Go! Go! Go!
24艘  长官
Twenty-four ships, sir.
几乎是三分之一的舰队了
That's almost a third of the fleet.
为什么?
Why?
他们在进行…
BOOMER: They were conducting research
人类与赛昂人的繁殖计划的研究
into Human-Cylon breeding programs.
一半人类一半赛昂人?
STARBUCK: Human-Cylon?
他们称做是"农场"
They call them farms.
伤口看起来没什么事
Your gunshot wound looks fine.
"农场"?好极了!
So, farms, that's great.
他们要干什么?
What were they gonna do?
让我怀上赛昂人的孩子?
Knock me up with some Cylon kid?
他们打算那么做
They were gonna try to.
到现在为止  我们还没有什么进展
We haven't been very successful so far.
想来是他们无法生育
Supposedly, they can't reproduce,
生理原因吧
you know, biologically,
所以想尽一切办法来繁衍后代
so they've been trying every which way to produce offspring.
为什么?
Why?
生育  是神的戒律之一
Procreation, that's one of God's commandments.
子孙满堂
"Be fruitful. "
我们试过  但我们无法生育  所以我们决定…
We can't fulfill it. We've tried. So we decided...
强奸人类中的女性
To rape human women.
除非是你自愿怀孕
You know, if you agreed to bear children, it'd be voluntary.
也许还可以给你找个你喜欢的对象
Maybe even set you up with someone you like.
就像你俩的孩子吗?
Like you two kids?
我们不同
We're different.
那是他妈的什么意思?
What the frak is that supposed to mean?
他们的理论就是...
They have this theory.
他们缺少的一样东西就是爱
Maybe the one thing they were missing was love.
所以莎伦和我...
So Sharon and I,
我们被撮合在一起...
we're set up...
让你们恋爱?
To fall in love?
他们没问过苏尚是否想恋爱  知道吗?
They didn't ask Sue-Shaun if she wanted to fall in love, all right?
他们把一根管子放在了她的体内 然后把她和一台机器连到了一起
They put a tube in her, and they hooked her up to a machine!
他们知道你是谁  卡拉
They know who you are, Kara.
你是一个特殊的人
You're special.
李·奥本告诉过你
Leoben told you that.
你有你的宿命
You have a destiny.
星芭儿  另一个伤疤是怎么回事?
HELO: Starbuck, what's this second scar?
不知道
I don't know.
我现在也不想知道
I don't think I wanna know now.
你知道?
You know?
不知道
No.
这些"农场"里有多少女性?
All right, how many women do they have at these farms?
几百人  也许几千人
Hundreds. Maybe thousands.
不清楚  我还没查看那些数据
I don't know. I haven't accessed that data.
我们这么办吧
Here's what we do.
驾驶那架重型突袭机  载满士兵
Take the Heavy Raider, cram it full of ground troops,
去寻找下一个解放的"农场"
find out where the next farm is, liberate it, then the next,
然后接着找下去...
and the next, and the next.
不  不  你来卡布里卡不是为了做这些事
No. No, that's not why you came to Caprica.
去找地球
Go find Earth.
那你呢?
What about you?
你说过你需要专家的指点
You said you needed professional advice.
我们会挺过去的
We'll muddle through.
目前来说还应付得来
We've managed so far.
他们会杀了你
They'll kill you.
你会死在这里  这你是知道的
You'll die here. You know that.
很多人都死在了这里
A lot of people died here,
我这么说吧  如果我死在了这里
but I'll tell you this: If I'm gonna die here,
临死之前
I'm gonna take out every last one of those frakking farms
我会把那些该死的"农场"都毁掉
before I do.
我不会把你丢在这里
I'm not gonna leave you here.
你说你会回来的  还记得吗?
You said you were gonna come back, remember?
我等着你
I'm gonna hold you to it.
我会回来的
I'm coming back.
我说到...
I said it.
做到
I meant it.
恩  好
Yeah, okay.
嗨
Hey.
注意安全
Be safe.
我们回家吧
Let's go home.